<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud-Composer on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-composer/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud-Composer on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-composer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>gcloud SDK 243.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-243-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-243-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 243.0.0 introduces several breaking changes, including the deprecation of &lt;code&gt;gcloud ml-engine&lt;/code&gt; in favor of &lt;code&gt;gcloud ai-platform&lt;/code&gt; and flag renames for AI Platform and Compute Engine. Key new features include extensive GA promotions for Compute Engine flags and command groups, new IP alias support for Cloud Composer, and Cloud Run add-on management for Kubernetes Engine. Minor security updates and command restructuring for Cloud Tasks were also implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 241.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 241.0.0 introduces a breaking change requiring the &lt;code&gt;--runtime&lt;/code&gt; flag for new Cloud Functions deployments and deprecates legacy network creation in Compute Engine. This release includes critical security updates, patching &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;CVE-2019-1002101&lt;/code&gt; and removing vulnerable older &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; versions. It also delivers numerous new features and promotions to GA/beta across services like Cloud Composer, BigQuery, Cloud Memorystore, Kubernetes Engine, and adds authenticated push subscriptions for Cloud Pub/Sub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 228.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-228-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-228-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 228.0.0 introduces several new beta features and promotes existing ones to GA across Compute Engine, Cloud Composer, Cloud DNS, and Kubernetes Engine. A notable breaking change is the deprecation of the &lt;code&gt;--full&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud endpoints operations describe&lt;/code&gt;. Additionally, the Java SDK for App Engine has been updated to version 1.9.70.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 222.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-222-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-222-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Google Cloud SDK update 222.0.0 deprecates the &lt;code&gt;gcloud container builds&lt;/code&gt; command group, urging migration to &lt;code&gt;gcloud builds&lt;/code&gt;. It introduces several new features, including private DNS zones, custom Airflow/image versions for Cloud Composer, and enhanced disk mounting for Compute Engine containers. A security update to &lt;code&gt;gcloud iam service-accounts keys create&lt;/code&gt; now prevents execution if a user lacks write access to output files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 220.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-220-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-220-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 220.0.0 introduces several breaking changes, including default disabling of legacy metadata APIs for new Kubernetes Engine node pools and deprecation of the internal &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; implementation for Python 3 support. Key security enhancements include default secure node pool configurations and KMS encryption for Dataproc clusters. New features span across various services, adding enhanced logging, Python version specification for Composer, and DML support for Cloud Spanner queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 209.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-209-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-209-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This chunk primarily updates the Compute Engine alpha API, introducing a new &amp;lsquo;Allocation&amp;rsquo; resource for pre-allocating specific instance configurations, which instances can then consume via &lt;code&gt;allocationAffinity&lt;/code&gt;. Additionally, it adds the ability to create instances from machine images using &lt;code&gt;sourceMachineImage&lt;/code&gt; and expands available GPU quota metrics to include NVIDIA P4 types. Various API descriptions were also updated for clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 208.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 208.0.0 introduces several new beta features, including Cloud Filestore and &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute network-endpoint-groups&lt;/code&gt; commands, along with numerous new flags for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions. Key changes include a warning about the default &lt;code&gt;--enable-ip-alias&lt;/code&gt; behavior in Kubernetes Engine and the removal of the &lt;code&gt;container/use_v1_api&lt;/code&gt; property. Significant internal groundwork was laid for new APIs like Cloud Composer, Service Networking, VPC Access, and a migration to &lt;code&gt;v1beta1&lt;/code&gt; for Binary Authorization attestors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 200.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-200-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-200-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 200.0.0 of the Google Cloud SDK introduces several breaking changes for Cloud DNS and Cloud Interconnect commands. It adds initial beta support for the Cloud Composer service, new flags for Cloud SQL external primary instances and replicas, and Stackdriver integration for Kubernetes Engine. Internally, the SDK underwent significant refactoring for logging, resource URI parsing, and Python 2/3 string handling compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>