<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud-Build on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-build/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud-Build on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-build/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>gcloud SDK 248.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-248-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-248-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 248.0.0 introduces several new flags and commands across various services, including &lt;code&gt;--ignore-file&lt;/code&gt; for Cloud Build, &lt;code&gt;--custom-vm-gen&lt;/code&gt; for Compute Engine, and a new &lt;code&gt;gcloud projects get-ancestors&lt;/code&gt; command. A notable breaking change is the removal of potentially harmful &lt;code&gt;initdb&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;resetdb&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;upgradedb&lt;/code&gt; subcommands for Cloud Composer, while &lt;code&gt;gcloud scheduler&lt;/code&gt; commands were promoted to General Availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 247.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-247-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-247-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release focuses on usability improvements and command enhancements across several services. Key additions include a new &lt;code&gt;--ignore-file&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud app deploy&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;gcloud builds submit&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;gcloud functions deploy&lt;/code&gt;, along with new update commands for Cloud Scheduler and HTTP task creation in Cloud Tasks. A notable breaking change is the removal of cluster deletion flags in Cloud Dataproc workflow templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 241.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 241.0.0 introduces a breaking change requiring the &lt;code&gt;--runtime&lt;/code&gt; flag for new Cloud Functions deployments and deprecates legacy network creation in Compute Engine. This release includes critical security updates, patching &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;CVE-2019-1002101&lt;/code&gt; and removing vulnerable older &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; versions. It also delivers numerous new features and promotions to GA/beta across services like Cloud Composer, BigQuery, Cloud Memorystore, Kubernetes Engine, and adds authenticated push subscriptions for Cloud Pub/Sub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 230.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-230-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-230-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 230.0.0 introduces several breaking changes, notably fixing symlink handling for App Engine and Cloud Functions source uploads, which may affect deployments. It deprecates First Generation Cloud SQL instances and renames Compute Engine Shielded VM flags. New features include an alternative &lt;code&gt;--zone&lt;/code&gt; flag for Cloud SQL instance creation and expanded Cloud Scheduler region support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 229.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-229-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-229-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 229.0.0 introduces significant new features, including an alpha &lt;code&gt;gcloud bq&lt;/code&gt; command group for BigQuery, Cloud Firestore index management, and Kaniko integration for Cloud Build with new flags. This release also includes the deprecation of HTTP/HTTPS health check flags in Compute Engine, the promotion of several flags and commands to beta and GA stability levels, and various updates and bug fixes for App Engine, Cloud Datastore, and Cloud Firestore emulators, alongside a &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; component update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cloud Build Triggers: Excluding Branches</title><link>https://lust.dev/2018/11/07/cloud-build-triggers-excluding-branches/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2018/11/07/cloud-build-triggers-excluding-branches/</guid><description>Exclude branches likes master from Cloud Build triggers</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 223.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-223-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-223-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release includes updates to the App Engine SDKs for Python (&lt;code&gt;1.9.78&lt;/code&gt;), Java (&lt;code&gt;1.9.68&lt;/code&gt;), and Go (&lt;code&gt;1.9.69&lt;/code&gt;), with the Go SDK update addressing a bug in Windows &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; deployments. Significant features promoted to beta include the &lt;code&gt;gcloud access-context-manager&lt;/code&gt; command group for Cloud Access Context Manager and Node Auto-Provisioning for Kubernetes Engine via the &lt;code&gt;--enable-autoprovisioning&lt;/code&gt; flag. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;gcloud builds submit&lt;/code&gt; command now defaults to &lt;code&gt;--config=cloudbuild.yaml&lt;/code&gt; if no other configuration or tag is provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 220.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-220-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-220-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 220.0.0 introduces several breaking changes, including default disabling of legacy metadata APIs for new Kubernetes Engine node pools and deprecation of the internal &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; implementation for Python 3 support. Key security enhancements include default secure node pool configurations and KMS encryption for Dataproc clusters. New features span across various services, adding enhanced logging, Python version specification for Composer, and DML support for Cloud Spanner queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 210.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-210-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-210-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 210.0.0 introduces several breaking changes related to Container Builder command group renames and deprecations, along with changes to Kubernetes Engine cluster creation defaults. Key new features include the promotion of Compute Engine &lt;code&gt;sole-tenancy&lt;/code&gt; commands to GA and the addition of new VPC flow logging flags for subnets. This release also includes significant groundwork for new services like Firestore and enhanced Cloud KMS capabilities, alongside various internal refactorings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>