<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud-Dataproc on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-dataproc/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud-Dataproc on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-dataproc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>gcloud SDK 258.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-258-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-258-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 258.0.0 introduces a breaking change by renaming a Compute Engine VM flag. It enhances security by disallowing unauthenticated callers by default for new Cloud Functions in beta, and adds new lifecycle management features for Cloud Dataproc clusters and Shielded VM options for Kubernetes Engine nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 251.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-251-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-251-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Google Cloud SDK release introduces significant breaking changes for Compute Engine and Kubernetes Engine, requiring explicit region/global flags for certain Compute Engine resources and defaulting new GKE clusters to VPC-native mode. Key new features include enhanced Kubernetes integration for Cloud Run with a new &lt;code&gt;--platform&lt;/code&gt; flag, Kerberos configuration options for Cloud Dataproc, and the promotion of GKE resource usage export to GA. Several bug fixes, such as for Cloud KMS and Firestore Emulator, along with API improvements like &lt;code&gt;PassAllFilter&lt;/code&gt; exposure in Bigtable, were also included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 240.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-240-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-240-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 240.0.0 introduces a breaking change by enabling Kubernetes Engine node auto-upgrade by default for new clusters and node-pools. Key new features include the &lt;code&gt;--impersonate-service-account&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt;, new commands for submitting Presto jobs to Cloud Dataproc, and expanded support for Compute Engine external and HA VPN gateways. Additionally, several features and flags across Cloud DNS, Compute Engine, and Kubernetes Engine have been promoted to Beta or GA stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 239.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-239-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-239-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 239.0.0 introduces new autoscaling policy management for Cloud Dataproc and promotes several Shielded VM features to GA in Compute Engine, including &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute instances get-shielded-identity&lt;/code&gt; and various &lt;code&gt;--shielded-*&lt;/code&gt; flags. This release also removes several deprecated &lt;code&gt;--shielded-vm-*&lt;/code&gt; flags, marking them as breaking changes for users still relying on them, and updates &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; versioning logic for Kubernetes Engine. No unannounced changes could be identified without the Git Diff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 236.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-236-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-236-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 236.0.0 introduces new functionality, including flags for Cloud Asset Inventory and Cloud Dataproc, and &lt;code&gt;debug()&lt;/code&gt; support for the Cloud Firestore Emulator. It promotes &lt;code&gt;services vpc-peerings&lt;/code&gt; to GA and improves error handling for &lt;code&gt;gcloud auth revoke&lt;/code&gt;. A minor breaking change removes the &lt;code&gt;auto-create-routes&lt;/code&gt; column from &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta compute networks peerings list&lt;/code&gt; output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 227.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 227.0.0 of the Google Cloud SDK introduces several breaking changes, notably the removal of deprecated &lt;code&gt;gcloud datastore&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gcloud container builds&lt;/code&gt; commands, and old Cloud IoT flags. This release focuses heavily on promoting various &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt; commands and flags to GA or beta across services like Cloud Functions, IoT, Spanner, and Compute Engine, while also adding new Bigtable filtering options and SparkR job support for Dataproc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 225.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-225-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-225-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 225.0.0 introduces several new features, including a global &lt;code&gt;--flags-file&lt;/code&gt; for complex flag values and enhanced retry options for Cloud Scheduler Pub/Sub jobs. Key promotions to GA include Cloud Spanner&amp;rsquo;s partitioned DML and Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s Router NATs, signaling increased stability and readiness across services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 221.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-221-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-221-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 221.0.0 introduces a breaking change by removing the deprecated &lt;code&gt;host&lt;/code&gt; argument from &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql users&lt;/code&gt; commands. It also brings several new features, including enhanced &lt;code&gt;gcloud app logs&lt;/code&gt; output for various runtimes and new flags for BigQuery dataset partition expiration and Cloud Spanner DML operations. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;--no-address&lt;/code&gt; flag for Cloud Dataproc and &lt;code&gt;--response&lt;/code&gt; flag for Compute Engine health-checks have been promoted to General Availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 220.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-220-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-220-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 220.0.0 introduces several breaking changes, including default disabling of legacy metadata APIs for new Kubernetes Engine node pools and deprecation of the internal &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; implementation for Python 3 support. Key security enhancements include default secure node pool configurations and KMS encryption for Dataproc clusters. New features span across various services, adding enhanced logging, Python version specification for Composer, and DML support for Cloud Spanner queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 218.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-218-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-218-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK &lt;code&gt;218.0.0&lt;/code&gt; introduces new features like Cloud Dataproc cluster import/export capabilities and expanded metadata flags for Kubernetes Engine, alongside a breaking change in the &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql instances list&lt;/code&gt; output. Significant promotions to General Availability and Beta occurred for Cloud Dataproc IAM policies and workflow templates, as well as Container Analysis image description and tag listing flags. Additionally, bug fixes were provided for Firebase Test Lab and Cloud Tools for PowerShell functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 214.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-214-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-214-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 214.0.0 introduces several breaking changes across Cloud Bigtable and Compute Engine, primarily involving command and flag renames or removals. Key new features include the promotion of numerous flags to GA for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions, and new private cluster options for Kubernetes Engine. Several services received updates to commands and improved functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 209.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-209-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-209-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This chunk primarily updates the Compute Engine alpha API, introducing a new &amp;lsquo;Allocation&amp;rsquo; resource for pre-allocating specific instance configurations, which instances can then consume via &lt;code&gt;allocationAffinity&lt;/code&gt;. Additionally, it adds the ability to create instances from machine images using &lt;code&gt;sourceMachineImage&lt;/code&gt; and expands available GPU quota metrics to include NVIDIA P4 types. Various API descriptions were also updated for clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 208.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 208.0.0 introduces several new beta features, including Cloud Filestore and &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute network-endpoint-groups&lt;/code&gt; commands, along with numerous new flags for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions. Key changes include a warning about the default &lt;code&gt;--enable-ip-alias&lt;/code&gt; behavior in Kubernetes Engine and the removal of the &lt;code&gt;container/use_v1_api&lt;/code&gt; property. Significant internal groundwork was laid for new APIs like Cloud Composer, Service Networking, VPC Access, and a migration to &lt;code&gt;v1beta1&lt;/code&gt; for Binary Authorization attestors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 203.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-203-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-203-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This SDK release includes a breaking change for Cloud SQL SSL certificate management, requiring a shift from &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql ssl-certs&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql ssl client-certs&lt;/code&gt;. New features allow file-based provisioning for Cloud Dataproc and advanced SSL server CA certificate rotation for Cloud SQL, with several Compute Engine flags promoted to beta. Unannounced changes reveal groundwork for features like &amp;lsquo;PushBlock&amp;rsquo; in Cloud Source Repositories and &lt;code&gt;max-pods-per-node&lt;/code&gt; in GKE, alongside significant API updates for Vision and Pub/Sub, and a notable schema reduction in the Video Intelligence API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>