<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tips and Tricks on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/tips-and-tricks/</link><description>Recent content in Tips and Tricks on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joseph Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/tips-and-tricks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Download InfoQ Books and PDFs without Login</title><link>https://lust.dev/2013/02/27/download-infoq-books-and-pdfs-without-login/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2013/02/27/download-infoq-books-and-pdfs-without-login/</guid><description>I just read Good Relationships by Michael Hunger. It was a great read to get up to speed on Spring Data Neo4J quickly, and also the only reference out there.
But, it requires you join InfoQ and give them your personal information to sell to whoever they please. No thanks.
Well, let&amp;#8217;s look at those links, what do they really do? Pop open the inspector and look at the link.</description></item><item><title>Windows Downloads without Windows Genuine Advantage</title><link>https://lust.dev/2011/07/02/windows-downloads-without-windows-genuine-advantage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2011/07/02/windows-downloads-without-windows-genuine-advantage/</guid><description>I found myself needing to download Virtual PC from Microsoft recently to test an application. I have a bonafide copy of windows, but my enterprise anti-virus won&amp;#8217;t let me run WGA. No problem, we&amp;#8217;ll just snoop around the MS site.
The following modal keeps prompting an ineffective download of WGA.
However, let&amp;#8217;s fire up Chrome and look at the html in the page.
Hmm, check out the div GenuineCheck_Validated_Successful.</description></item><item><title>Console2 Arrow Keys Madness</title><link>https://lust.dev/2011/04/02/console2-arrow-key-error/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2011/04/02/console2-arrow-key-error/</guid><description>I&amp;#8217;m writing to tell you how to fix this error since it just drove me mad for 20 minutes.
If you are an avid user of Console2, which any Windows user should be, you might notice one day that your arrow keys scroll up and down, rather than select the most recent command. Why the heck would that happen? It does not happen in the Microsoft cmd window, but it will in Cygwin and Cmd under Console2.</description></item></channel></rss>