<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud-Data-Catalog on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-data-catalog/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud-Data-Catalog on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-data-catalog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>gcloud SDK 252.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-252-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-252-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 252.0.0 introduces significant enhancements across several services, including new Cloud Data Catalog commands for managing tags and searching resources. Key flags for Cloud Functions and Compute Engine, such as &lt;code&gt;--max-instances&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--source-snapshot&lt;/code&gt;, have been promoted to General Availability. Additionally, several IAM policy management commands and Workload Identity flags for Kubernetes Engine have advanced to beta, alongside a breaking change removing &lt;code&gt;--network-interface&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta compute start-iap-tunnel&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 242.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-242-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-242-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 242.0.0 of the Google Cloud SDK includes a critical security fix for &lt;code&gt;gcloud config config-helper&lt;/code&gt; to prevent stale identity tokens. Cloud Composer introduces breaking changes by deprecating potentially harmful database subcommands. The release also adds new features, such as IAP Tunneling by default for Compute Engine SSH/SCP, new flags for Data Catalog, IAM service accounts, and Compute Engine image deprecation controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 241.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 241.0.0 introduces a breaking change requiring the &lt;code&gt;--runtime&lt;/code&gt; flag for new Cloud Functions deployments and deprecates legacy network creation in Compute Engine. This release includes critical security updates, patching &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;CVE-2019-1002101&lt;/code&gt; and removing vulnerable older &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; versions. It also delivers numerous new features and promotions to GA/beta across services like Cloud Composer, BigQuery, Cloud Memorystore, Kubernetes Engine, and adds authenticated push subscriptions for Cloud Pub/Sub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>