<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bigquery on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/bigquery/</link><description>Recent content in Bigquery on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/bigquery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Google Cloud Event Bridge for Okta Syslogs</title><link>https://lust.dev/2025/12/03/okta-syslog-gcp-event-bridge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2025/12/03/okta-syslog-gcp-event-bridge/</guid><description>Okta natively integrates with AWS EventBridge, but what about Google Cloud users? Here&amp;rsquo;s how to bridge that gap and unlock real-time alerting, org-wide Okta dashboards, and BigQuery Okta event archives.</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 260.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-260-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-260-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 260.0.0 introduces breaking changes requiring the &lt;code&gt;--region&lt;/code&gt; flag for Cloud Dataproc and altering Cloud Run authentication. Significant new features include Shielded GKE Nodes for enhanced security, expanded BigQuery IAM policy management, and a new Policy Troubleshooter for IAM permissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 254.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-254-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-254-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 254.0.0 introduces significant advancements across several services. AI Platform and Compute Engine saw major flags and resource policies promoted to General Availability, enhancing training job configuration and disk management. Cloud Pub/Sub gained beta support for controlling message storage regions, alongside important bug fixes for Firestore Emulator, Cloud Run, and Cloud Storage to improve stability and user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 253.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-253-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-253-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;SDK 253.0.0 introduces several GA promotions, notably for Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s IAP tunnel, guest attributes, and HTTP/2 health checks, alongside new SSH key expiration flags. It also adds new BigQuery capabilities like scheduled queries and persistent UDFs. Key updates include a &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; security fix for CVE-2019-11246 and breaking changes involving flag removals in Cloud Run and a command deprecation in Compute Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 241.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 241.0.0 introduces a breaking change requiring the &lt;code&gt;--runtime&lt;/code&gt; flag for new Cloud Functions deployments and deprecates legacy network creation in Compute Engine. This release includes critical security updates, patching &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;CVE-2019-1002101&lt;/code&gt; and removing vulnerable older &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; versions. It also delivers numerous new features and promotions to GA/beta across services like Cloud Composer, BigQuery, Cloud Memorystore, Kubernetes Engine, and adds authenticated push subscriptions for Cloud Pub/Sub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 231.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-231-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-231-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 231.0.0 introduces several new features, including BigQuery BI Engine reservations, export/import functionality for the Cloud Datastore Emulator, and advanced disk configuration options in Compute Engine. Key flags were promoted to beta or GA across Compute Engine, Firebase Test Lab, and Kubernetes Engine, enhancing instance group management, disk creation, and test reliability. This release also updates the App Engine Python SDK and includes a breaking change related to Cloud SQL error messaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 229.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-229-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-229-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 229.0.0 introduces significant new features, including an alpha &lt;code&gt;gcloud bq&lt;/code&gt; command group for BigQuery, Cloud Firestore index management, and Kaniko integration for Cloud Build with new flags. This release also includes the deprecation of HTTP/HTTPS health check flags in Compute Engine, the promotion of several flags and commands to beta and GA stability levels, and various updates and bug fixes for App Engine, Cloud Datastore, and Cloud Firestore emulators, alongside a &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; component update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 225.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-225-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-225-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 225.0.0 introduces several new features, including a global &lt;code&gt;--flags-file&lt;/code&gt; for complex flag values and enhanced retry options for Cloud Scheduler Pub/Sub jobs. Key promotions to GA include Cloud Spanner&amp;rsquo;s partitioned DML and Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s Router NATs, signaling increased stability and readiness across services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 221.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-221-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-221-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 221.0.0 introduces a breaking change by removing the deprecated &lt;code&gt;host&lt;/code&gt; argument from &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql users&lt;/code&gt; commands. It also brings several new features, including enhanced &lt;code&gt;gcloud app logs&lt;/code&gt; output for various runtimes and new flags for BigQuery dataset partition expiration and Cloud Spanner DML operations. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;--no-address&lt;/code&gt; flag for Cloud Dataproc and &lt;code&gt;--response&lt;/code&gt; flag for Compute Engine health-checks have been promoted to General Availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>