<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud-Functions on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-functions/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud-Functions on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-functions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upgrading to Google Cloud Functions 2nd Gen</title><link>https://lust.dev/2022/08/04/upgrading-cloud-functions-gen2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2022/08/04/upgrading-cloud-functions-gen2/</guid><description>Take the leap, upgrade to 2nd Gen Google Cloud Functions!</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 252.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-252-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-252-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 252.0.0 introduces significant enhancements across several services, including new Cloud Data Catalog commands for managing tags and searching resources. Key flags for Cloud Functions and Compute Engine, such as &lt;code&gt;--max-instances&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--source-snapshot&lt;/code&gt;, have been promoted to General Availability. Additionally, several IAM policy management commands and Workload Identity flags for Kubernetes Engine have advanced to beta, alongside a breaking change removing &lt;code&gt;--network-interface&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta compute start-iap-tunnel&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 250.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-250-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-250-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 250.0.0 features a breaking change in &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute networks update&lt;/code&gt;, which now polls for operation completion, requiring &lt;code&gt;--async&lt;/code&gt; for immediate return. New functionalities include data import/export for Cloud Memorystore Redis, Cloud KMS integration for Pub/Sub topics, and a &lt;code&gt;core/disable_file_logging&lt;/code&gt; property. This release also promotes various commands and flags in Compute Engine, Cloud Key Management Service, and Stackdriver Kubernetes Engine Monitoring to GA or beta, enhancing feature stability and availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 247.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-247-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-247-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release focuses on usability improvements and command enhancements across several services. Key additions include a new &lt;code&gt;--ignore-file&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud app deploy&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;gcloud builds submit&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;gcloud functions deploy&lt;/code&gt;, along with new update commands for Cloud Scheduler and HTTP task creation in Cloud Tasks. A notable breaking change is the removal of cluster deletion flags in Cloud Dataproc workflow templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 246.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-246-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-246-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 246.0.0 introduces a breaking change by removing &lt;code&gt;bps-&lt;/code&gt; prefixed bandwidth flag values for &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute interconnects attachments&lt;/code&gt; commands. Significant new features include the &lt;code&gt;--billing-project&lt;/code&gt; flag across all &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt; commands, &lt;code&gt;--allow-unauthenticated&lt;/code&gt; for Cloud Functions deployment, and &lt;code&gt;--accelerator&lt;/code&gt; for Compute Engine instances with containers. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;gcloud tasks&lt;/code&gt; command group and the &lt;code&gt;--expiration-period&lt;/code&gt; flag for Pub/Sub subscriptions have been promoted to General Availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 241.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 241.0.0 introduces a breaking change requiring the &lt;code&gt;--runtime&lt;/code&gt; flag for new Cloud Functions deployments and deprecates legacy network creation in Compute Engine. This release includes critical security updates, patching &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;CVE-2019-1002101&lt;/code&gt; and removing vulnerable older &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; versions. It also delivers numerous new features and promotions to GA/beta across services like Cloud Composer, BigQuery, Cloud Memorystore, Kubernetes Engine, and adds authenticated push subscriptions for Cloud Pub/Sub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 227.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 227.0.0 of the Google Cloud SDK introduces several breaking changes, notably the removal of deprecated &lt;code&gt;gcloud datastore&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gcloud container builds&lt;/code&gt; commands, and old Cloud IoT flags. This release focuses heavily on promoting various &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt; commands and flags to GA or beta across services like Cloud Functions, IoT, Spanner, and Compute Engine, while also adding new Bigtable filtering options and SparkR job support for Dataproc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 215.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-215-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-215-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 215.0.0 introduces a breaking change in Cloud SQL by removing the default for &lt;code&gt;--database-version&lt;/code&gt; during instance creation. Significant new features include Python 3 support for App Engine, new &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta firestore&lt;/code&gt; commands for managing imports/exports, and the promotion of Pub/Sub Snapshot &amp;amp; Seek features to beta. Due to the absence of a Git Diff, &lt;code&gt;filePath&lt;/code&gt; information and &lt;code&gt;unannouncedChanges&lt;/code&gt; could not be identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 214.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-214-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-214-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 214.0.0 introduces several breaking changes across Cloud Bigtable and Compute Engine, primarily involving command and flag renames or removals. Key new features include the promotion of numerous flags to GA for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions, and new private cluster options for Kubernetes Engine. Several services received updates to commands and improved functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 209.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-209-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-209-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This chunk primarily updates the Compute Engine alpha API, introducing a new &amp;lsquo;Allocation&amp;rsquo; resource for pre-allocating specific instance configurations, which instances can then consume via &lt;code&gt;allocationAffinity&lt;/code&gt;. Additionally, it adds the ability to create instances from machine images using &lt;code&gt;sourceMachineImage&lt;/code&gt; and expands available GPU quota metrics to include NVIDIA P4 types. Various API descriptions were also updated for clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 208.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 208.0.0 introduces several new beta features, including Cloud Filestore and &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute network-endpoint-groups&lt;/code&gt; commands, along with numerous new flags for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions. Key changes include a warning about the default &lt;code&gt;--enable-ip-alias&lt;/code&gt; behavior in Kubernetes Engine and the removal of the &lt;code&gt;container/use_v1_api&lt;/code&gt; property. Significant internal groundwork was laid for new APIs like Cloud Composer, Service Networking, VPC Access, and a migration to &lt;code&gt;v1beta1&lt;/code&gt; for Binary Authorization attestors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 205.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-205-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-205-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 205.0.0 introduces new flags for Cloud Bigtable, Datastore index management commands, and promotes several Cloud Interconnect and Compute Engine features to GA. A significant security update enhances SSH key validation for Compute Engine metadata. The release also includes extensive Python 2/3 compatibility refactoring, new API clients for Cloud File and Source Repositories, and foundational improvements to Calliope&amp;rsquo;s argument parsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>