<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ExtJs on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/extjs/</link><description>Recent content in ExtJs on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/extjs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Open ExtJs Menu on Mouseover</title><link>https://lust.dev/2011/07/06/open-extjs-menu-on-mouseover/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2011/07/06/open-extjs-menu-on-mouseover/</guid><description>Would you believe there is no way to open an ExtJs toolbar menu when you hover over the corresponding button? This functionality is all over the ExtJs homepage, but not in their framework. Boo! Nope, nothing without pulling the buttons out of the toolbar (see here), which is a no go for existing applications.
So, I present you with the HoverButton. It is just like the standard button, but hides after 250ms of mouseout from the button or the opened menu.</description></item><item><title>ExtJs Field getForm() Override</title><link>https://lust.dev/2011/06/19/extjs-field-getform-override/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2011/06/19/extjs-field-getform-override/</guid><description>When using the DOM directly, if you have the element reference to an &amp;lt;INPUT&amp;gt; object, you can reference its parent via el.form. However, in ExtJs, there is no such accessor for the form of field. The following ExtJs override adds the getForm() method to a field which will search upward through the ExtDOM until it finds a parent form, or hits a recursion depth of 10.
Example usage:
// Example useage var myField = Ext.</description></item><item><title>Update ExtJs TabPanel Tab Title</title><link>https://lust.dev/2011/05/01/update-extjs-tab-title/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2011/05/01/update-extjs-tab-title/</guid><description>Isn’t ExtJs the cat’s meow? I think so, but many cats have hairballs. For ExtJs, this includes missing the ability to update the title of a TabPanel tab title once it has been rendered. Sure, you can find the item and title properties for your tab post-render, but that won’t update your page. You need to crawl the DOM. I’ve created an update to do just this.
Just paste the below override in your code and you can then call the setTabTitle(tabNo,newTitle) method to update a given tab title.</description></item><item><title>Extjs Hidden Textfield Missing</title><link>https://lust.dev/2011/04/03/extjs-hidden-textfield-missing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2011/04/03/extjs-hidden-textfield-missing/</guid><description>I love ExtJS, but some days it just does not love me back.
For instance, if you have a hidden textfield, and you don&amp;rsquo;t set the width property, it won&amp;rsquo;t be added to your form. Sure, you say, why would you need the width for a hidden input? Well, ExtJS thinks you might call myHiddenTextfield.show() some day, so it still needs to put it in there with a width. No width, no love.</description></item></channel></rss>