<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud-Datastore-Emulator on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-datastore-emulator/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud-Datastore-Emulator on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-datastore-emulator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>gcloud SDK 231.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-231-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-231-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 231.0.0 introduces several new features, including BigQuery BI Engine reservations, export/import functionality for the Cloud Datastore Emulator, and advanced disk configuration options in Compute Engine. Key flags were promoted to beta or GA across Compute Engine, Firebase Test Lab, and Kubernetes Engine, enhancing instance group management, disk creation, and test reliability. This release also updates the App Engine Python SDK and includes a breaking change related to Cloud SQL error messaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 214.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-214-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-214-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 214.0.0 introduces several breaking changes across Cloud Bigtable and Compute Engine, primarily involving command and flag renames or removals. Key new features include the promotion of numerous flags to GA for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions, and new private cluster options for Kubernetes Engine. Several services received updates to commands and improved functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 208.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 208.0.0 introduces several new beta features, including Cloud Filestore and &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute network-endpoint-groups&lt;/code&gt; commands, along with numerous new flags for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions. Key changes include a warning about the default &lt;code&gt;--enable-ip-alias&lt;/code&gt; behavior in Kubernetes Engine and the removal of the &lt;code&gt;container/use_v1_api&lt;/code&gt; property. Significant internal groundwork was laid for new APIs like Cloud Composer, Service Networking, VPC Access, and a migration to &lt;code&gt;v1beta1&lt;/code&gt; for Binary Authorization attestors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 202.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-202-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-202-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 202.0.0 introduces breaking changes to Cloud Composer disk size, Compute Engine interconnects commands, Firebase Test Lab flags, and Compute Engine sole-tenancy node deletion. Key new features include GA promotion for Compute Engine flow logs, beta promotion for sole-tenancy, and a new Kubernetes Engine &lt;code&gt;--disk-type&lt;/code&gt; flag. Significant unannounced changes include the removal of the Cloud IoT v1 API client, groundwork for Category Manager, and several hidden features for Compute Engine resource policies, Dataproc, and DLP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>