<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud-Pub-Sub on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-pub-sub/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud-Pub-Sub on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-pub-sub/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>gcloud SDK 259.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-259-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-259-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 259.0.0 of the Cloud SDK focuses on expanding authentication capabilities with service account impersonation and Compute Engine service account support for identity tokens. It also introduces Cloud KMS integration for Pub/Sub topic encryption, adds the ability to specify storage locations for Compute Engine image imports, and promotes GKE Hub commands to beta, alongside updating &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; for Python 3.x compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 256.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-256-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-256-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This SDK update includes a breaking change that reverts Kubernetes Engine cluster creation to Routes mode by default, now requiring the &lt;code&gt;--enable-ip-alias&lt;/code&gt; flag for VPC-Native mode. Key new features enhance Cloud Bigtable with complex GC policies, Cloud Dataflow with KMS key support, and Cloud Pub/Sub with authenticated push subscriptions. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;gcloud iap&lt;/code&gt; command group is now in beta, and a new &lt;code&gt;gcloud active-directory&lt;/code&gt; command group has been introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 254.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-254-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-254-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 254.0.0 introduces significant advancements across several services. AI Platform and Compute Engine saw major flags and resource policies promoted to General Availability, enhancing training job configuration and disk management. Cloud Pub/Sub gained beta support for controlling message storage regions, alongside important bug fixes for Firestore Emulator, Cloud Run, and Cloud Storage to improve stability and user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 252.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-252-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-252-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 252.0.0 introduces significant enhancements across several services, including new Cloud Data Catalog commands for managing tags and searching resources. Key flags for Cloud Functions and Compute Engine, such as &lt;code&gt;--max-instances&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--source-snapshot&lt;/code&gt;, have been promoted to General Availability. Additionally, several IAM policy management commands and Workload Identity flags for Kubernetes Engine have advanced to beta, alongside a breaking change removing &lt;code&gt;--network-interface&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta compute start-iap-tunnel&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 250.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-250-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-250-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 250.0.0 features a breaking change in &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute networks update&lt;/code&gt;, which now polls for operation completion, requiring &lt;code&gt;--async&lt;/code&gt; for immediate return. New functionalities include data import/export for Cloud Memorystore Redis, Cloud KMS integration for Pub/Sub topics, and a &lt;code&gt;core/disable_file_logging&lt;/code&gt; property. This release also promotes various commands and flags in Compute Engine, Cloud Key Management Service, and Stackdriver Kubernetes Engine Monitoring to GA or beta, enhancing feature stability and availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 241.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 241.0.0 introduces a breaking change requiring the &lt;code&gt;--runtime&lt;/code&gt; flag for new Cloud Functions deployments and deprecates legacy network creation in Compute Engine. This release includes critical security updates, patching &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;CVE-2019-1002101&lt;/code&gt; and removing vulnerable older &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; versions. It also delivers numerous new features and promotions to GA/beta across services like Cloud Composer, BigQuery, Cloud Memorystore, Kubernetes Engine, and adds authenticated push subscriptions for Cloud Pub/Sub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 227.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 227.0.0 of the Google Cloud SDK introduces several breaking changes, notably the removal of deprecated &lt;code&gt;gcloud datastore&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gcloud container builds&lt;/code&gt; commands, and old Cloud IoT flags. This release focuses heavily on promoting various &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt; commands and flags to GA or beta across services like Cloud Functions, IoT, Spanner, and Compute Engine, while also adding new Bigtable filtering options and SparkR job support for Dataproc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 215.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-215-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-215-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 215.0.0 introduces a breaking change in Cloud SQL by removing the default for &lt;code&gt;--database-version&lt;/code&gt; during instance creation. Significant new features include Python 3 support for App Engine, new &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta firestore&lt;/code&gt; commands for managing imports/exports, and the promotion of Pub/Sub Snapshot &amp;amp; Seek features to beta. Due to the absence of a Git Diff, &lt;code&gt;filePath&lt;/code&gt; information and &lt;code&gt;unannouncedChanges&lt;/code&gt; could not be identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>