<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>App-Engine on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/app-engine/</link><description>Recent content in App-Engine on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/app-engine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quick Upgrade Trick for App Engine Java 17</title><link>https://lust.dev/2024/10/01/quick-upgrade-app-engine-java-17/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2024/10/01/quick-upgrade-app-engine-java-17/</guid><description>Quickly modernize your App Engine Java 8 codebase to run on Java 17!</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 247.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-247-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-247-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release focuses on usability improvements and command enhancements across several services. Key additions include a new &lt;code&gt;--ignore-file&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud app deploy&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;gcloud builds submit&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;gcloud functions deploy&lt;/code&gt;, along with new update commands for Cloud Scheduler and HTTP task creation in Cloud Tasks. A notable breaking change is the removal of cluster deletion flags in Cloud Dataproc workflow templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 240.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-240-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-240-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 240.0.0 introduces a breaking change by enabling Kubernetes Engine node auto-upgrade by default for new clusters and node-pools. Key new features include the &lt;code&gt;--impersonate-service-account&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt;, new commands for submitting Presto jobs to Cloud Dataproc, and expanded support for Compute Engine external and HA VPN gateways. Additionally, several features and flags across Cloud DNS, Compute Engine, and Kubernetes Engine have been promoted to Beta or GA stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 238.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-238-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-238-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Google Cloud SDK update, version 238.0.0, primarily focuses on promoting existing features to GA or Beta for various services, including &lt;code&gt;gcloud access-context-manager&lt;/code&gt; and several flags across Cloud Dataproc, Functions, and ML Engine. Key new capabilities include the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; field in &lt;code&gt;app.yaml&lt;/code&gt; for App Engine Go runtimes and the &lt;code&gt;--enable-shielded-containers&lt;/code&gt; flag for GKE. A notable breaking change removes the &lt;code&gt;unrestricted-services&lt;/code&gt; field from Cloud Access Context Manager, now defaulting to all services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 228.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-228-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-228-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 228.0.0 introduces several new beta features and promotes existing ones to GA across Compute Engine, Cloud Composer, Cloud DNS, and Kubernetes Engine. A notable breaking change is the deprecation of the &lt;code&gt;--full&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud endpoints operations describe&lt;/code&gt;. Additionally, the Java SDK for App Engine has been updated to version 1.9.70.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 226.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-226-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-226-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 226.0.0 introduces a breaking change for Cloud Spanner&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta spanner rows&lt;/code&gt; command, now requiring &lt;code&gt;--flags-file&lt;/code&gt; for array values with the &lt;code&gt;--data&lt;/code&gt; flag. New features include an App Engine command group for configuration migration and the beta release of the Cloud Firestore Emulator. Additionally, Cloud Endpoints deployment behavior has been adjusted regarding service enablement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 223.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-223-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-223-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release includes updates to the App Engine SDKs for Python (&lt;code&gt;1.9.78&lt;/code&gt;), Java (&lt;code&gt;1.9.68&lt;/code&gt;), and Go (&lt;code&gt;1.9.69&lt;/code&gt;), with the Go SDK update addressing a bug in Windows &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; deployments. Significant features promoted to beta include the &lt;code&gt;gcloud access-context-manager&lt;/code&gt; command group for Cloud Access Context Manager and Node Auto-Provisioning for Kubernetes Engine via the &lt;code&gt;--enable-autoprovisioning&lt;/code&gt; flag. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;gcloud builds submit&lt;/code&gt; command now defaults to &lt;code&gt;--config=cloudbuild.yaml&lt;/code&gt; if no other configuration or tag is provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 221.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-221-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-221-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 221.0.0 introduces a breaking change by removing the deprecated &lt;code&gt;host&lt;/code&gt; argument from &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql users&lt;/code&gt; commands. It also brings several new features, including enhanced &lt;code&gt;gcloud app logs&lt;/code&gt; output for various runtimes and new flags for BigQuery dataset partition expiration and Cloud Spanner DML operations. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;--no-address&lt;/code&gt; flag for Cloud Dataproc and &lt;code&gt;--response&lt;/code&gt; flag for Compute Engine health-checks have been promoted to General Availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 216.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-216-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-216-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 216.0.0 brings significant promotions to General Availability, including &lt;code&gt;gcloud bigtable instances&lt;/code&gt; commands, &lt;code&gt;gcloud redis&lt;/code&gt; for Memorystore, and Compute Engine commands for creating/updating instances with containers. It also updates the App Engine Go SDK to 1.9.68 and deprecates the &lt;code&gt;gcloud services operations list&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 215.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-215-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-215-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 215.0.0 introduces a breaking change in Cloud SQL by removing the default for &lt;code&gt;--database-version&lt;/code&gt; during instance creation. Significant new features include Python 3 support for App Engine, new &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta firestore&lt;/code&gt; commands for managing imports/exports, and the promotion of Pub/Sub Snapshot &amp;amp; Seek features to beta. Due to the absence of a Git Diff, &lt;code&gt;filePath&lt;/code&gt; information and &lt;code&gt;unannouncedChanges&lt;/code&gt; could not be identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 211.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-211-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-211-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 211.0.0 introduces breaking changes for App Engine, removing automated &lt;code&gt;app.yaml&lt;/code&gt; generation and standardizing file exclusions with &lt;code&gt;.gcloudignore&lt;/code&gt;. New features include commands for Cloud Datastore index management and globbing support for Cloud Deployment Manager imports. Additionally, several &lt;code&gt;--network-tier&lt;/code&gt; flags across Compute Engine commands have been promoted to General Availability, marking them as stable for production use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 209.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-209-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-209-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This chunk primarily updates the Compute Engine alpha API, introducing a new &amp;lsquo;Allocation&amp;rsquo; resource for pre-allocating specific instance configurations, which instances can then consume via &lt;code&gt;allocationAffinity&lt;/code&gt;. Additionally, it adds the ability to create instances from machine images using &lt;code&gt;sourceMachineImage&lt;/code&gt; and expands available GPU quota metrics to include NVIDIA P4 types. Various API descriptions were also updated for clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 208.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 208.0.0 introduces several new beta features, including Cloud Filestore and &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute network-endpoint-groups&lt;/code&gt; commands, along with numerous new flags for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions. Key changes include a warning about the default &lt;code&gt;--enable-ip-alias&lt;/code&gt; behavior in Kubernetes Engine and the removal of the &lt;code&gt;container/use_v1_api&lt;/code&gt; property. Significant internal groundwork was laid for new APIs like Cloud Composer, Service Networking, VPC Access, and a migration to &lt;code&gt;v1beta1&lt;/code&gt; for Binary Authorization attestors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 205.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-205-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-205-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 205.0.0 introduces new flags for Cloud Bigtable, Datastore index management commands, and promotes several Cloud Interconnect and Compute Engine features to GA. A significant security update enhances SSH key validation for Compute Engine metadata. The release also includes extensive Python 2/3 compatibility refactoring, new API clients for Cloud File and Source Repositories, and foundational improvements to Calliope&amp;rsquo;s argument parsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 202.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-202-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-202-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 202.0.0 introduces breaking changes to Cloud Composer disk size, Compute Engine interconnects commands, Firebase Test Lab flags, and Compute Engine sole-tenancy node deletion. Key new features include GA promotion for Compute Engine flow logs, beta promotion for sole-tenancy, and a new Kubernetes Engine &lt;code&gt;--disk-type&lt;/code&gt; flag. Significant unannounced changes include the removal of the Cloud IoT v1 API client, groundwork for Category Manager, and several hidden features for Compute Engine resource policies, Dataproc, and DLP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>