<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud-Bigtable on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-bigtable/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud-Bigtable on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-bigtable/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>gcloud SDK 256.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-256-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-256-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This SDK update includes a breaking change that reverts Kubernetes Engine cluster creation to Routes mode by default, now requiring the &lt;code&gt;--enable-ip-alias&lt;/code&gt; flag for VPC-Native mode. Key new features enhance Cloud Bigtable with complex GC policies, Cloud Dataflow with KMS key support, and Cloud Pub/Sub with authenticated push subscriptions. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;gcloud iap&lt;/code&gt; command group is now in beta, and a new &lt;code&gt;gcloud active-directory&lt;/code&gt; command group has been introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 227.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 227.0.0 of the Google Cloud SDK introduces several breaking changes, notably the removal of deprecated &lt;code&gt;gcloud datastore&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gcloud container builds&lt;/code&gt; commands, and old Cloud IoT flags. This release focuses heavily on promoting various &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt; commands and flags to GA or beta across services like Cloud Functions, IoT, Spanner, and Compute Engine, while also adding new Bigtable filtering options and SparkR job support for Dataproc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 216.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-216-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-216-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 216.0.0 brings significant promotions to General Availability, including &lt;code&gt;gcloud bigtable instances&lt;/code&gt; commands, &lt;code&gt;gcloud redis&lt;/code&gt; for Memorystore, and Compute Engine commands for creating/updating instances with containers. It also updates the App Engine Go SDK to 1.9.68 and deprecates the &lt;code&gt;gcloud services operations list&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 214.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-214-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-214-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 214.0.0 introduces several breaking changes across Cloud Bigtable and Compute Engine, primarily involving command and flag renames or removals. Key new features include the promotion of numerous flags to GA for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions, and new private cluster options for Kubernetes Engine. Several services received updates to commands and improved functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 205.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-205-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-205-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 205.0.0 introduces new flags for Cloud Bigtable, Datastore index management commands, and promotes several Cloud Interconnect and Compute Engine features to GA. A significant security update enhances SSH key validation for Compute Engine metadata. The release also includes extensive Python 2/3 compatibility refactoring, new API clients for Cloud File and Source Repositories, and foundational improvements to Calliope&amp;rsquo;s argument parsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 201.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-201-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-201-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Google Cloud SDK release introduces a breaking change to the default TPU accelerator type for Compute Engine. Key new features include iOS app testing in Firebase Test Lab, IAM policy management for Cloud Bigtable, and new &lt;code&gt;--labels&lt;/code&gt; functionality for Compute Engine instance templates. Additionally, the SDK contains numerous unannounced changes, such as full API integration for Cloud IoT, advanced DLP job trigger capabilities, and groundwork for Compute Engine resource policies and Cloud Functions runtimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>