<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud-Sdk on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-sdk/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud-Sdk on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-sdk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>gcloud SDK 259.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-259-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-259-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 259.0.0 of the Cloud SDK focuses on expanding authentication capabilities with service account impersonation and Compute Engine service account support for identity tokens. It also introduces Cloud KMS integration for Pub/Sub topic encryption, adds the ability to specify storage locations for Compute Engine image imports, and promotes GKE Hub commands to beta, alongside updating &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; for Python 3.x compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 250.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-250-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-250-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 250.0.0 features a breaking change in &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute networks update&lt;/code&gt;, which now polls for operation completion, requiring &lt;code&gt;--async&lt;/code&gt; for immediate return. New functionalities include data import/export for Cloud Memorystore Redis, Cloud KMS integration for Pub/Sub topics, and a &lt;code&gt;core/disable_file_logging&lt;/code&gt; property. This release also promotes various commands and flags in Compute Engine, Cloud Key Management Service, and Stackdriver Kubernetes Engine Monitoring to GA or beta, enhancing feature stability and availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 249.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-249-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-249-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release introduces a new &lt;code&gt;gcloud auth print-identity-token&lt;/code&gt; command for easier identity token retrieval and adds a &lt;code&gt;survey/disable_prompts&lt;/code&gt; property to opt out of surveys. Additionally, &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;export&lt;/code&gt; commands for &lt;code&gt;backend-services&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;url-maps&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;forwarding-rules&lt;/code&gt; have been promoted to beta, indicating increased stability for these functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 246.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-246-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-246-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 246.0.0 introduces a breaking change by removing &lt;code&gt;bps-&lt;/code&gt; prefixed bandwidth flag values for &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute interconnects attachments&lt;/code&gt; commands. Significant new features include the &lt;code&gt;--billing-project&lt;/code&gt; flag across all &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt; commands, &lt;code&gt;--allow-unauthenticated&lt;/code&gt; for Cloud Functions deployment, and &lt;code&gt;--accelerator&lt;/code&gt; for Compute Engine instances with containers. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;gcloud tasks&lt;/code&gt; command group and the &lt;code&gt;--expiration-period&lt;/code&gt; flag for Pub/Sub subscriptions have been promoted to General Availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 245.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-245-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-245-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 245.0.0 introduces two breaking changes by removing deprecated Kubernetes Engine flags and properties, making &lt;code&gt;new_scopes_behavior&lt;/code&gt; the default. Key new features include the &lt;code&gt;gcloud alpha survey&lt;/code&gt; command, new export options for Cloud Asset Inventory, beta support for Cloud SQL flags in Cloud Run, and new &lt;code&gt;pause&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;resume&lt;/code&gt; commands for Cloud Scheduler jobs. Additionally, the App Engine Java SDK was updated to version 1.9.74, and the Compute Engine &lt;code&gt;--instance-redistribution-type&lt;/code&gt; flag was promoted to beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 240.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-240-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-240-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 240.0.0 introduces a breaking change by enabling Kubernetes Engine node auto-upgrade by default for new clusters and node-pools. Key new features include the &lt;code&gt;--impersonate-service-account&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt;, new commands for submitting Presto jobs to Cloud Dataproc, and expanded support for Compute Engine external and HA VPN gateways. Additionally, several features and flags across Cloud DNS, Compute Engine, and Kubernetes Engine have been promoted to Beta or GA stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 227.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 227.0.0 of the Google Cloud SDK introduces several breaking changes, notably the removal of deprecated &lt;code&gt;gcloud datastore&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gcloud container builds&lt;/code&gt; commands, and old Cloud IoT flags. This release focuses heavily on promoting various &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt; commands and flags to GA or beta across services like Cloud Functions, IoT, Spanner, and Compute Engine, while also adding new Bigtable filtering options and SparkR job support for Dataproc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 225.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-225-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-225-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 225.0.0 introduces several new features, including a global &lt;code&gt;--flags-file&lt;/code&gt; for complex flag values and enhanced retry options for Cloud Scheduler Pub/Sub jobs. Key promotions to GA include Cloud Spanner&amp;rsquo;s partitioned DML and Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s Router NATs, signaling increased stability and readiness across services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 220.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-220-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-220-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 220.0.0 introduces several breaking changes, including default disabling of legacy metadata APIs for new Kubernetes Engine node pools and deprecation of the internal &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; implementation for Python 3 support. Key security enhancements include default secure node pool configurations and KMS encryption for Dataproc clusters. New features span across various services, adding enhanced logging, Python version specification for Composer, and DML support for Cloud Spanner queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 208.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 208.0.0 introduces several new beta features, including Cloud Filestore and &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute network-endpoint-groups&lt;/code&gt; commands, along with numerous new flags for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions. Key changes include a warning about the default &lt;code&gt;--enable-ip-alias&lt;/code&gt; behavior in Kubernetes Engine and the removal of the &lt;code&gt;container/use_v1_api&lt;/code&gt; property. Significant internal groundwork was laid for new APIs like Cloud Composer, Service Networking, VPC Access, and a migration to &lt;code&gt;v1beta1&lt;/code&gt; for Binary Authorization attestors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>