<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amazon S3 on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/amazon-s3/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon S3 on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joseph Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/amazon-s3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Don’t use Git to Deploy Code</title><link>https://lust.dev/2015/02/28/dont-use-git-to-deploy-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2015/02/28/dont-use-git-to-deploy-code/</guid><description>Just don&amp;#8217;t. If you can&amp;#8217;t reason why, please stop developing code critical to your business.
When it works, it works Git is great. Push here, pull there. It works so well that you might be fatuously convinced it&amp;#8217;s the perfect tool to deploy production code. Even worse, it might appear to work well at this task, further reinforcing your choice However, the Achilles Heel of any DVCS is your origin provider.</description></item><item><title>Subdomain SSL Certificate Verification on Route 53</title><link>https://lust.dev/2014/03/16/subdomain-ssl-certificate-verification-on-route-53/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2014/03/16/subdomain-ssl-certificate-verification-on-route-53/</guid><description>Sadly a GoDaddy User I use GoDaddy for a few domains and some SSL. Every time I need to set something up, it is like pulling teeth. First you&amp;#8217;ve got to get through four layers of sales pitches, cross sells, and upsells. Then you finally get to the admin UI&amp;#8217;s. Not the UI, the UI&amp;#8217;s. Each one of them appears to have been designed by team with a different design philosophy.</description></item><item><title>LogRotate Apache Logs to Amazon S3</title><link>https://lust.dev/2012/07/15/logrotate-apache-logs-to-amazon-s3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2012/07/15/logrotate-apache-logs-to-amazon-s3/</guid><description>Legacy Log Rotation before gzip &amp;amp; scp I recently moved my site RunPartner to Amazon Web Services (AWS) from DreamHost because for just a few more peanuts a month I got a ton of enterprise grade services, and the server does not crash randomly any more. 😊
I&amp;#8217;m loving AWS, but one thing I wanted to do was consolidate all logs to S3. Let&amp;#8217;s say your site gets SlashDotted or Pinned.</description></item></channel></rss>