<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Google-Cloud-Platform on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/google-cloud-platform/</link><description>Recent content in Google-Cloud-Platform on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/google-cloud-platform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Google Cloud Event Bridge for Okta Syslogs</title><link>https://lust.dev/2025/12/03/okta-syslog-gcp-event-bridge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2025/12/03/okta-syslog-gcp-event-bridge/</guid><description>Okta natively integrates with AWS EventBridge, but what about Google Cloud users? Here&amp;rsquo;s how to bridge that gap and unlock real-time alerting, org-wide Okta dashboards, and BigQuery Okta event archives.</description></item><item><title>Quick Upgrade Trick for App Engine Java 17</title><link>https://lust.dev/2024/10/01/quick-upgrade-app-engine-java-17/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2024/10/01/quick-upgrade-app-engine-java-17/</guid><description>Quickly modernize your App Engine Java 8 codebase to run on Java 17!</description></item><item><title>Upgrading to Google Cloud Functions 2nd Gen</title><link>https://lust.dev/2022/08/04/upgrading-cloud-functions-gen2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2022/08/04/upgrading-cloud-functions-gen2/</guid><description>Take the leap, upgrade to 2nd Gen Google Cloud Functions!</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 260.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-260-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-260-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 260.0.0 introduces breaking changes requiring the &lt;code&gt;--region&lt;/code&gt; flag for Cloud Dataproc and altering Cloud Run authentication. Significant new features include Shielded GKE Nodes for enhanced security, expanded BigQuery IAM policy management, and a new Policy Troubleshooter for IAM permissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 259.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-259-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-259-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 259.0.0 of the Cloud SDK focuses on expanding authentication capabilities with service account impersonation and Compute Engine service account support for identity tokens. It also introduces Cloud KMS integration for Pub/Sub topic encryption, adds the ability to specify storage locations for Compute Engine image imports, and promotes GKE Hub commands to beta, alongside updating &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; for Python 3.x compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 258.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-258-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-258-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 258.0.0 introduces a breaking change by renaming a Compute Engine VM flag. It enhances security by disallowing unauthenticated callers by default for new Cloud Functions in beta, and adds new lifecycle management features for Cloud Dataproc clusters and Shielded VM options for Kubernetes Engine nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 257.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-257-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-257-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud SDK 257.0.0 removes support for &lt;code&gt;multistore&lt;/code&gt; format credentials, requiring a specific upgrade process for older installations. It also updates the Cloud Firestore emulator to &lt;code&gt;v1.7.0&lt;/code&gt; with WebChannel support and adds a &lt;code&gt;--disable-database-encryption&lt;/code&gt; flag to &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta container clusters update&lt;/code&gt; for Kubernetes Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 256.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-256-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-256-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This SDK update includes a breaking change that reverts Kubernetes Engine cluster creation to Routes mode by default, now requiring the &lt;code&gt;--enable-ip-alias&lt;/code&gt; flag for VPC-Native mode. Key new features enhance Cloud Bigtable with complex GC policies, Cloud Dataflow with KMS key support, and Cloud Pub/Sub with authenticated push subscriptions. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;gcloud iap&lt;/code&gt; command group is now in beta, and a new &lt;code&gt;gcloud active-directory&lt;/code&gt; command group has been introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 255.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-255-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-255-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 255.0.0 introduces a breaking change requiring the &lt;code&gt;--platform&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta run&lt;/code&gt; commands. Key new features include the &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute diagnose&lt;/code&gt; command group and a new &lt;code&gt;access-policy&lt;/code&gt; content type for Cloud Asset Inventory. This release also promotes &lt;code&gt;gcloud container binauthz&lt;/code&gt; to GA and resolves bugs in Compute Engine network-endpoint-groups and Firebase Test Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 254.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-254-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-254-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 254.0.0 introduces significant advancements across several services. AI Platform and Compute Engine saw major flags and resource policies promoted to General Availability, enhancing training job configuration and disk management. Cloud Pub/Sub gained beta support for controlling message storage regions, alongside important bug fixes for Firestore Emulator, Cloud Run, and Cloud Storage to improve stability and user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 253.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-253-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-253-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;SDK 253.0.0 introduces several GA promotions, notably for Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s IAP tunnel, guest attributes, and HTTP/2 health checks, alongside new SSH key expiration flags. It also adds new BigQuery capabilities like scheduled queries and persistent UDFs. Key updates include a &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; security fix for CVE-2019-11246 and breaking changes involving flag removals in Cloud Run and a command deprecation in Compute Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 252.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-252-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-252-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 252.0.0 introduces significant enhancements across several services, including new Cloud Data Catalog commands for managing tags and searching resources. Key flags for Cloud Functions and Compute Engine, such as &lt;code&gt;--max-instances&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--source-snapshot&lt;/code&gt;, have been promoted to General Availability. Additionally, several IAM policy management commands and Workload Identity flags for Kubernetes Engine have advanced to beta, alongside a breaking change removing &lt;code&gt;--network-interface&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta compute start-iap-tunnel&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 251.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-251-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-251-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Google Cloud SDK release introduces significant breaking changes for Compute Engine and Kubernetes Engine, requiring explicit region/global flags for certain Compute Engine resources and defaulting new GKE clusters to VPC-native mode. Key new features include enhanced Kubernetes integration for Cloud Run with a new &lt;code&gt;--platform&lt;/code&gt; flag, Kerberos configuration options for Cloud Dataproc, and the promotion of GKE resource usage export to GA. Several bug fixes, such as for Cloud KMS and Firestore Emulator, along with API improvements like &lt;code&gt;PassAllFilter&lt;/code&gt; exposure in Bigtable, were also included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 250.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-250-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-250-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 250.0.0 features a breaking change in &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute networks update&lt;/code&gt;, which now polls for operation completion, requiring &lt;code&gt;--async&lt;/code&gt; for immediate return. New functionalities include data import/export for Cloud Memorystore Redis, Cloud KMS integration for Pub/Sub topics, and a &lt;code&gt;core/disable_file_logging&lt;/code&gt; property. This release also promotes various commands and flags in Compute Engine, Cloud Key Management Service, and Stackdriver Kubernetes Engine Monitoring to GA or beta, enhancing feature stability and availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 249.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-249-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-249-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release introduces a new &lt;code&gt;gcloud auth print-identity-token&lt;/code&gt; command for easier identity token retrieval and adds a &lt;code&gt;survey/disable_prompts&lt;/code&gt; property to opt out of surveys. Additionally, &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;export&lt;/code&gt; commands for &lt;code&gt;backend-services&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;url-maps&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;forwarding-rules&lt;/code&gt; have been promoted to beta, indicating increased stability for these functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 248.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-248-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-248-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 248.0.0 introduces several new flags and commands across various services, including &lt;code&gt;--ignore-file&lt;/code&gt; for Cloud Build, &lt;code&gt;--custom-vm-gen&lt;/code&gt; for Compute Engine, and a new &lt;code&gt;gcloud projects get-ancestors&lt;/code&gt; command. A notable breaking change is the removal of potentially harmful &lt;code&gt;initdb&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;resetdb&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;upgradedb&lt;/code&gt; subcommands for Cloud Composer, while &lt;code&gt;gcloud scheduler&lt;/code&gt; commands were promoted to General Availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 247.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-247-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-247-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release focuses on usability improvements and command enhancements across several services. Key additions include a new &lt;code&gt;--ignore-file&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud app deploy&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;gcloud builds submit&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;gcloud functions deploy&lt;/code&gt;, along with new update commands for Cloud Scheduler and HTTP task creation in Cloud Tasks. A notable breaking change is the removal of cluster deletion flags in Cloud Dataproc workflow templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 246.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-246-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-246-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 246.0.0 introduces a breaking change by removing &lt;code&gt;bps-&lt;/code&gt; prefixed bandwidth flag values for &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute interconnects attachments&lt;/code&gt; commands. Significant new features include the &lt;code&gt;--billing-project&lt;/code&gt; flag across all &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt; commands, &lt;code&gt;--allow-unauthenticated&lt;/code&gt; for Cloud Functions deployment, and &lt;code&gt;--accelerator&lt;/code&gt; for Compute Engine instances with containers. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;gcloud tasks&lt;/code&gt; command group and the &lt;code&gt;--expiration-period&lt;/code&gt; flag for Pub/Sub subscriptions have been promoted to General Availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 245.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-245-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-245-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 245.0.0 introduces two breaking changes by removing deprecated Kubernetes Engine flags and properties, making &lt;code&gt;new_scopes_behavior&lt;/code&gt; the default. Key new features include the &lt;code&gt;gcloud alpha survey&lt;/code&gt; command, new export options for Cloud Asset Inventory, beta support for Cloud SQL flags in Cloud Run, and new &lt;code&gt;pause&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;resume&lt;/code&gt; commands for Cloud Scheduler jobs. Additionally, the App Engine Java SDK was updated to version 1.9.74, and the Compute Engine &lt;code&gt;--instance-redistribution-type&lt;/code&gt; flag was promoted to beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 244.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-244-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-244-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 244.0.0 introduces new features across Cloud Scheduler, Kubernetes Engine, and Vision API. Key updates include enhanced authentication controls for Cloud Scheduler HTTP jobs, a new flag for Kubernetes Engine nodepool metadata server visibility, and new object and text detection functionalities for the Vision API. The &lt;code&gt;gcloud container subnets list-usable&lt;/code&gt; command for Kubernetes Engine was also promoted to GA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 243.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-243-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-243-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 243.0.0 introduces several breaking changes, including the deprecation of &lt;code&gt;gcloud ml-engine&lt;/code&gt; in favor of &lt;code&gt;gcloud ai-platform&lt;/code&gt; and flag renames for AI Platform and Compute Engine. Key new features include extensive GA promotions for Compute Engine flags and command groups, new IP alias support for Cloud Composer, and Cloud Run add-on management for Kubernetes Engine. Minor security updates and command restructuring for Cloud Tasks were also implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 242.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-242-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-242-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 242.0.0 of the Google Cloud SDK includes a critical security fix for &lt;code&gt;gcloud config config-helper&lt;/code&gt; to prevent stale identity tokens. Cloud Composer introduces breaking changes by deprecating potentially harmful database subcommands. The release also adds new features, such as IAP Tunneling by default for Compute Engine SSH/SCP, new flags for Data Catalog, IAM service accounts, and Compute Engine image deprecation controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 241.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 241.0.0 introduces a breaking change requiring the &lt;code&gt;--runtime&lt;/code&gt; flag for new Cloud Functions deployments and deprecates legacy network creation in Compute Engine. This release includes critical security updates, patching &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;CVE-2019-1002101&lt;/code&gt; and removing vulnerable older &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; versions. It also delivers numerous new features and promotions to GA/beta across services like Cloud Composer, BigQuery, Cloud Memorystore, Kubernetes Engine, and adds authenticated push subscriptions for Cloud Pub/Sub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 240.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-240-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-240-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 240.0.0 introduces a breaking change by enabling Kubernetes Engine node auto-upgrade by default for new clusters and node-pools. Key new features include the &lt;code&gt;--impersonate-service-account&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt;, new commands for submitting Presto jobs to Cloud Dataproc, and expanded support for Compute Engine external and HA VPN gateways. Additionally, several features and flags across Cloud DNS, Compute Engine, and Kubernetes Engine have been promoted to Beta or GA stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 239.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-239-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-239-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 239.0.0 introduces new autoscaling policy management for Cloud Dataproc and promotes several Shielded VM features to GA in Compute Engine, including &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute instances get-shielded-identity&lt;/code&gt; and various &lt;code&gt;--shielded-*&lt;/code&gt; flags. This release also removes several deprecated &lt;code&gt;--shielded-vm-*&lt;/code&gt; flags, marking them as breaking changes for users still relying on them, and updates &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; versioning logic for Kubernetes Engine. No unannounced changes could be identified without the Git Diff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 238.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-238-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-238-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Google Cloud SDK update, version 238.0.0, primarily focuses on promoting existing features to GA or Beta for various services, including &lt;code&gt;gcloud access-context-manager&lt;/code&gt; and several flags across Cloud Dataproc, Functions, and ML Engine. Key new capabilities include the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; field in &lt;code&gt;app.yaml&lt;/code&gt; for App Engine Go runtimes and the &lt;code&gt;--enable-shielded-containers&lt;/code&gt; flag for GKE. A notable breaking change removes the &lt;code&gt;unrestricted-services&lt;/code&gt; field from Cloud Access Context Manager, now defaulting to all services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 237.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-237-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-237-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release primarily focuses on bug fixes, including a critical fix for a Windows installer crash, BigQuery timestamp formatting, and Cloud Dataproc field visibility. It also updates key components like &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; to 4.37 and &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; to 1.11.7 (adding more versions), while introducing new Compute Engine features such as reduced disk size limits, new options for compute commitments, and enhanced &lt;code&gt;instance-groups&lt;/code&gt; listing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 236.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-236-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-236-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 236.0.0 introduces new functionality, including flags for Cloud Asset Inventory and Cloud Dataproc, and &lt;code&gt;debug()&lt;/code&gt; support for the Cloud Firestore Emulator. It promotes &lt;code&gt;services vpc-peerings&lt;/code&gt; to GA and improves error handling for &lt;code&gt;gcloud auth revoke&lt;/code&gt;. A minor breaking change removes the &lt;code&gt;auto-create-routes&lt;/code&gt; column from &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta compute networks peerings list&lt;/code&gt; output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 233.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-233-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-233-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 233.0.0 delivers significant enhancements including new job configuration flags for Cloud Dataflow and Cloud ML Engine, and promotes several key features to General Availability across Cloud Filestore, Pub/Sub, and Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s instance groups and network configurations. Additionally, it updates the Cloud Firestore Emulator with new RPCs and logging, fixes a &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql connect&lt;/code&gt; whitelisting issue, and updates the &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 232.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-232-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-232-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release includes several breaking changes, notably the deprecation of &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute instance-groups managed set-autohealing&lt;/code&gt; and a new hard requirement for &lt;code&gt;gcloud container clusters create&lt;/code&gt; when using the CloudRun add-on. Key new features include the &lt;code&gt;--enable-display-device&lt;/code&gt; flag for Compute Engine instances and &lt;code&gt;--max-pods-per-node&lt;/code&gt; for GKE clusters. Additionally, several IAM policy commands for Compute Engine resources have been promoted to GA, and a problematic fix for &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql connect&lt;/code&gt; was rolled back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 231.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-231-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-231-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 231.0.0 introduces several new features, including BigQuery BI Engine reservations, export/import functionality for the Cloud Datastore Emulator, and advanced disk configuration options in Compute Engine. Key flags were promoted to beta or GA across Compute Engine, Firebase Test Lab, and Kubernetes Engine, enhancing instance group management, disk creation, and test reliability. This release also updates the App Engine Python SDK and includes a breaking change related to Cloud SQL error messaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 230.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-230-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-230-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 230.0.0 introduces several breaking changes, notably fixing symlink handling for App Engine and Cloud Functions source uploads, which may affect deployments. It deprecates First Generation Cloud SQL instances and renames Compute Engine Shielded VM flags. New features include an alternative &lt;code&gt;--zone&lt;/code&gt; flag for Cloud SQL instance creation and expanded Cloud Scheduler region support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 229.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-229-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-229-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 229.0.0 introduces significant new features, including an alpha &lt;code&gt;gcloud bq&lt;/code&gt; command group for BigQuery, Cloud Firestore index management, and Kaniko integration for Cloud Build with new flags. This release also includes the deprecation of HTTP/HTTPS health check flags in Compute Engine, the promotion of several flags and commands to beta and GA stability levels, and various updates and bug fixes for App Engine, Cloud Datastore, and Cloud Firestore emulators, alongside a &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; component update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 228.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-228-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-228-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 228.0.0 introduces several new beta features and promotes existing ones to GA across Compute Engine, Cloud Composer, Cloud DNS, and Kubernetes Engine. A notable breaking change is the deprecation of the &lt;code&gt;--full&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;gcloud endpoints operations describe&lt;/code&gt;. Additionally, the Java SDK for App Engine has been updated to version 1.9.70.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 227.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-227-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 227.0.0 of the Google Cloud SDK introduces several breaking changes, notably the removal of deprecated &lt;code&gt;gcloud datastore&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gcloud container builds&lt;/code&gt; commands, and old Cloud IoT flags. This release focuses heavily on promoting various &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt; commands and flags to GA or beta across services like Cloud Functions, IoT, Spanner, and Compute Engine, while also adding new Bigtable filtering options and SparkR job support for Dataproc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 226.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-226-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-226-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 226.0.0 introduces a breaking change for Cloud Spanner&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta spanner rows&lt;/code&gt; command, now requiring &lt;code&gt;--flags-file&lt;/code&gt; for array values with the &lt;code&gt;--data&lt;/code&gt; flag. New features include an App Engine command group for configuration migration and the beta release of the Cloud Firestore Emulator. Additionally, Cloud Endpoints deployment behavior has been adjusted regarding service enablement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 225.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-225-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-225-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 225.0.0 introduces several new features, including a global &lt;code&gt;--flags-file&lt;/code&gt; for complex flag values and enhanced retry options for Cloud Scheduler Pub/Sub jobs. Key promotions to GA include Cloud Spanner&amp;rsquo;s partitioned DML and Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s Router NATs, signaling increased stability and readiness across services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cloud Build Triggers: Excluding Branches</title><link>https://lust.dev/2018/11/07/cloud-build-triggers-excluding-branches/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/2018/11/07/cloud-build-triggers-excluding-branches/</guid><description>Exclude branches likes master from Cloud Build triggers</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 224.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-224-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-224-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This SDK release includes significant breaking changes for Container Builder users, deprecating &lt;code&gt;container-builder-local&lt;/code&gt; and redirecting &lt;code&gt;gcloud container builds&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;gcloud builds&lt;/code&gt;. It also promotes the &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute instances create --hostname&lt;/code&gt; flag to beta and updates the App Engine Python and Go SDKs to their latest versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 223.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-223-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-223-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release includes updates to the App Engine SDKs for Python (&lt;code&gt;1.9.78&lt;/code&gt;), Java (&lt;code&gt;1.9.68&lt;/code&gt;), and Go (&lt;code&gt;1.9.69&lt;/code&gt;), with the Go SDK update addressing a bug in Windows &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; deployments. Significant features promoted to beta include the &lt;code&gt;gcloud access-context-manager&lt;/code&gt; command group for Cloud Access Context Manager and Node Auto-Provisioning for Kubernetes Engine via the &lt;code&gt;--enable-autoprovisioning&lt;/code&gt; flag. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;gcloud builds submit&lt;/code&gt; command now defaults to &lt;code&gt;--config=cloudbuild.yaml&lt;/code&gt; if no other configuration or tag is provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 222.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-222-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-222-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Google Cloud SDK update 222.0.0 deprecates the &lt;code&gt;gcloud container builds&lt;/code&gt; command group, urging migration to &lt;code&gt;gcloud builds&lt;/code&gt;. It introduces several new features, including private DNS zones, custom Airflow/image versions for Cloud Composer, and enhanced disk mounting for Compute Engine containers. A security update to &lt;code&gt;gcloud iam service-accounts keys create&lt;/code&gt; now prevents execution if a user lacks write access to output files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 221.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-221-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-221-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 221.0.0 introduces a breaking change by removing the deprecated &lt;code&gt;host&lt;/code&gt; argument from &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql users&lt;/code&gt; commands. It also brings several new features, including enhanced &lt;code&gt;gcloud app logs&lt;/code&gt; output for various runtimes and new flags for BigQuery dataset partition expiration and Cloud Spanner DML operations. Additionally, the &lt;code&gt;--no-address&lt;/code&gt; flag for Cloud Dataproc and &lt;code&gt;--response&lt;/code&gt; flag for Compute Engine health-checks have been promoted to General Availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 220.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-220-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-220-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 220.0.0 introduces several breaking changes, including default disabling of legacy metadata APIs for new Kubernetes Engine node pools and deprecation of the internal &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; implementation for Python 3 support. Key security enhancements include default secure node pool configurations and KMS encryption for Dataproc clusters. New features span across various services, adding enhanced logging, Python version specification for Composer, and DML support for Cloud Spanner queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 219.0.1 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-219-0-1-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-219-0-1-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Google Cloud SDK update 219.0.1 primarily focuses on promoting several Compute Engine and Kubernetes Engine features to beta or GA, notably enhancing KMS key support for disk/image protection and adding private cluster capabilities for GKE. It also includes an update to the App Engine Python SDK and a fix for Unicode issues in the core Cloud SDK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 218.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-218-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-218-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK &lt;code&gt;218.0.0&lt;/code&gt; introduces new features like Cloud Dataproc cluster import/export capabilities and expanded metadata flags for Kubernetes Engine, alongside a breaking change in the &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql instances list&lt;/code&gt; output. Significant promotions to General Availability and Beta occurred for Cloud Dataproc IAM policies and workflow templates, as well as Container Analysis image description and tag listing flags. Additionally, bug fixes were provided for Firebase Test Lab and Cloud Tools for PowerShell functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 217.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-217-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-217-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release introduces a breaking change with the renaming of the &lt;code&gt;--reserved-ranges&lt;/code&gt; flag in &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta services vpc-peerings&lt;/code&gt;. New features include enhanced IP range reservation and disk description capabilities for Compute Engine, along with metadata flags for Kubernetes Engine node pools and clusters. Several core components, including the App Engine Java SDK, gsutil, and kubectl, have also been updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 216.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-216-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-216-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 216.0.0 brings significant promotions to General Availability, including &lt;code&gt;gcloud bigtable instances&lt;/code&gt; commands, &lt;code&gt;gcloud redis&lt;/code&gt; for Memorystore, and Compute Engine commands for creating/updating instances with containers. It also updates the App Engine Go SDK to 1.9.68 and deprecates the &lt;code&gt;gcloud services operations list&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 215.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-215-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-215-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 215.0.0 introduces a breaking change in Cloud SQL by removing the default for &lt;code&gt;--database-version&lt;/code&gt; during instance creation. Significant new features include Python 3 support for App Engine, new &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta firestore&lt;/code&gt; commands for managing imports/exports, and the promotion of Pub/Sub Snapshot &amp;amp; Seek features to beta. Due to the absence of a Git Diff, &lt;code&gt;filePath&lt;/code&gt; information and &lt;code&gt;unannouncedChanges&lt;/code&gt; could not be identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 214.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-214-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-214-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 214.0.0 introduces several breaking changes across Cloud Bigtable and Compute Engine, primarily involving command and flag renames or removals. Key new features include the promotion of numerous flags to GA for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions, and new private cluster options for Kubernetes Engine. Several services received updates to commands and improved functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 213.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-213-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-213-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 213.0.0 introduces breaking changes for Cloud Datastore index management, deprecating &lt;code&gt;create-indexes&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;cleanup-indexes&lt;/code&gt; in favor of the newly GA-promoted &lt;code&gt;gcloud datastore indexes&lt;/code&gt; command group. It also adds a &lt;code&gt;--timeout&lt;/code&gt; flag to &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql operations wait&lt;/code&gt; and enhances Kubernetes Engine commands, including the promotion of the &lt;code&gt;--disk-type&lt;/code&gt; flag to GA and improved output for degraded clusters. Additionally, the App Engine Python SDK was updated to version &lt;code&gt;1.9.74&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 211.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-211-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-211-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 211.0.0 introduces breaking changes for App Engine, removing automated &lt;code&gt;app.yaml&lt;/code&gt; generation and standardizing file exclusions with &lt;code&gt;.gcloudignore&lt;/code&gt;. New features include commands for Cloud Datastore index management and globbing support for Cloud Deployment Manager imports. Additionally, several &lt;code&gt;--network-tier&lt;/code&gt; flags across Compute Engine commands have been promoted to General Availability, marking them as stable for production use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 210.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-210-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-210-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 210.0.0 introduces several breaking changes related to Container Builder command group renames and deprecations, along with changes to Kubernetes Engine cluster creation defaults. Key new features include the promotion of Compute Engine &lt;code&gt;sole-tenancy&lt;/code&gt; commands to GA and the addition of new VPC flow logging flags for subnets. This release also includes significant groundwork for new services like Firestore and enhanced Cloud KMS capabilities, alongside various internal refactorings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 209.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-209-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-209-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This chunk primarily updates the Compute Engine alpha API, introducing a new &amp;lsquo;Allocation&amp;rsquo; resource for pre-allocating specific instance configurations, which instances can then consume via &lt;code&gt;allocationAffinity&lt;/code&gt;. Additionally, it adds the ability to create instances from machine images using &lt;code&gt;sourceMachineImage&lt;/code&gt; and expands available GPU quota metrics to include NVIDIA P4 types. Various API descriptions were also updated for clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 208.0.2 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-2-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-2-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This release is a hotfix primarily addressing crashes within the &lt;code&gt;dev_appserver&lt;/code&gt; component. It also updates the SDK&amp;rsquo;s internal version to &lt;code&gt;208.0.2&lt;/code&gt; and includes an internal revision timestamp update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 208.0.1 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-1-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-1-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This &lt;code&gt;208.0.1&lt;/code&gt; release is a hotfix specifically addressing &lt;code&gt;gcloud dataproc&lt;/code&gt; crashes. The fix involved significant refactoring of the internal YAML processing for Dataproc workflow templates, leading to the removal of the &lt;code&gt;--source&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--destination&lt;/code&gt; CLI flags and associated schema validation logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 208.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-208-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 208.0.0 introduces several new beta features, including Cloud Filestore and &lt;code&gt;gcloud compute network-endpoint-groups&lt;/code&gt; commands, along with numerous new flags for Compute Engine and Cloud Functions. Key changes include a warning about the default &lt;code&gt;--enable-ip-alias&lt;/code&gt; behavior in Kubernetes Engine and the removal of the &lt;code&gt;container/use_v1_api&lt;/code&gt; property. Significant internal groundwork was laid for new APIs like Cloud Composer, Service Networking, VPC Access, and a migration to &lt;code&gt;v1beta1&lt;/code&gt; for Binary Authorization attestors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 205.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-205-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-205-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 205.0.0 introduces new flags for Cloud Bigtable, Datastore index management commands, and promotes several Cloud Interconnect and Compute Engine features to GA. A significant security update enhances SSH key validation for Compute Engine metadata. The release also includes extensive Python 2/3 compatibility refactoring, new API clients for Cloud File and Source Repositories, and foundational improvements to Calliope&amp;rsquo;s argument parsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 203.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-203-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-203-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This SDK release includes a breaking change for Cloud SQL SSL certificate management, requiring a shift from &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql ssl-certs&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql ssl client-certs&lt;/code&gt;. New features allow file-based provisioning for Cloud Dataproc and advanced SSL server CA certificate rotation for Cloud SQL, with several Compute Engine flags promoted to beta. Unannounced changes reveal groundwork for features like &amp;lsquo;PushBlock&amp;rsquo; in Cloud Source Repositories and &lt;code&gt;max-pods-per-node&lt;/code&gt; in GKE, alongside significant API updates for Vision and Pub/Sub, and a notable schema reduction in the Video Intelligence API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 202.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-202-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-202-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 202.0.0 introduces breaking changes to Cloud Composer disk size, Compute Engine interconnects commands, Firebase Test Lab flags, and Compute Engine sole-tenancy node deletion. Key new features include GA promotion for Compute Engine flow logs, beta promotion for sole-tenancy, and a new Kubernetes Engine &lt;code&gt;--disk-type&lt;/code&gt; flag. Significant unannounced changes include the removal of the Cloud IoT v1 API client, groundwork for Category Manager, and several hidden features for Compute Engine resource policies, Dataproc, and DLP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 201.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-201-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-201-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Google Cloud SDK release introduces a breaking change to the default TPU accelerator type for Compute Engine. Key new features include iOS app testing in Firebase Test Lab, IAM policy management for Cloud Bigtable, and new &lt;code&gt;--labels&lt;/code&gt; functionality for Compute Engine instance templates. Additionally, the SDK contains numerous unannounced changes, such as full API integration for Cloud IoT, advanced DLP job trigger capabilities, and groundwork for Compute Engine resource policies and Cloud Functions runtimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 200.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-200-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-200-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 200.0.0 of the Google Cloud SDK introduces several breaking changes for Cloud DNS and Cloud Interconnect commands. It adds initial beta support for the Cloud Composer service, new flags for Cloud SQL external primary instances and replicas, and Stackdriver integration for Kubernetes Engine. Internally, the SDK underwent significant refactoring for logging, resource URI parsing, and Python 2/3 string handling compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#unannounced-changes"&gt;Unannounced Changes 🕵️&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>