<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud-Firestore-Emulator on lust.dev</title><link>https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-firestore-emulator/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud-Firestore-Emulator on lust.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Joe Lust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lust.dev/tags/cloud-firestore-emulator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>gcloud SDK 260.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-260-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-260-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 260.0.0 introduces breaking changes requiring the &lt;code&gt;--region&lt;/code&gt; flag for Cloud Dataproc and altering Cloud Run authentication. Significant new features include Shielded GKE Nodes for enhanced security, expanded BigQuery IAM policy management, and a new Policy Troubleshooter for IAM permissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 257.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-257-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-257-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud SDK 257.0.0 removes support for &lt;code&gt;multistore&lt;/code&gt; format credentials, requiring a specific upgrade process for older installations. It also updates the Cloud Firestore emulator to &lt;code&gt;v1.7.0&lt;/code&gt; with WebChannel support and adds a &lt;code&gt;--disable-database-encryption&lt;/code&gt; flag to &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta container clusters update&lt;/code&gt; for Kubernetes Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 253.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-253-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-253-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;SDK 253.0.0 introduces several GA promotions, notably for Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s IAP tunnel, guest attributes, and HTTP/2 health checks, alongside new SSH key expiration flags. It also adds new BigQuery capabilities like scheduled queries and persistent UDFs. Key updates include a &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; security fix for CVE-2019-11246 and breaking changes involving flag removals in Cloud Run and a command deprecation in Compute Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 251.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-251-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-251-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Google Cloud SDK release introduces significant breaking changes for Compute Engine and Kubernetes Engine, requiring explicit region/global flags for certain Compute Engine resources and defaulting new GKE clusters to VPC-native mode. Key new features include enhanced Kubernetes integration for Cloud Run with a new &lt;code&gt;--platform&lt;/code&gt; flag, Kerberos configuration options for Cloud Dataproc, and the promotion of GKE resource usage export to GA. Several bug fixes, such as for Cloud KMS and Firestore Emulator, along with API improvements like &lt;code&gt;PassAllFilter&lt;/code&gt; exposure in Bigtable, were also included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 248.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-248-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-248-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 248.0.0 introduces several new flags and commands across various services, including &lt;code&gt;--ignore-file&lt;/code&gt; for Cloud Build, &lt;code&gt;--custom-vm-gen&lt;/code&gt; for Compute Engine, and a new &lt;code&gt;gcloud projects get-ancestors&lt;/code&gt; command. A notable breaking change is the removal of potentially harmful &lt;code&gt;initdb&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;resetdb&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;upgradedb&lt;/code&gt; subcommands for Cloud Composer, while &lt;code&gt;gcloud scheduler&lt;/code&gt; commands were promoted to General Availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 242.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-242-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-242-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Version 242.0.0 of the Google Cloud SDK includes a critical security fix for &lt;code&gt;gcloud config config-helper&lt;/code&gt; to prevent stale identity tokens. Cloud Composer introduces breaking changes by deprecating potentially harmful database subcommands. The release also adds new features, such as IAP Tunneling by default for Compute Engine SSH/SCP, new flags for Data Catalog, IAM service accounts, and Compute Engine image deprecation controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 241.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-241-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK version 241.0.0 introduces a breaking change requiring the &lt;code&gt;--runtime&lt;/code&gt; flag for new Cloud Functions deployments and deprecates legacy network creation in Compute Engine. This release includes critical security updates, patching &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;CVE-2019-1002101&lt;/code&gt; and removing vulnerable older &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; versions. It also delivers numerous new features and promotions to GA/beta across services like Cloud Composer, BigQuery, Cloud Memorystore, Kubernetes Engine, and adds authenticated push subscriptions for Cloud Pub/Sub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 236.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-236-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-236-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 236.0.0 introduces new functionality, including flags for Cloud Asset Inventory and Cloud Dataproc, and &lt;code&gt;debug()&lt;/code&gt; support for the Cloud Firestore Emulator. It promotes &lt;code&gt;services vpc-peerings&lt;/code&gt; to GA and improves error handling for &lt;code&gt;gcloud auth revoke&lt;/code&gt;. A minor breaking change removes the &lt;code&gt;auto-create-routes&lt;/code&gt; column from &lt;code&gt;gcloud beta compute networks peerings list&lt;/code&gt; output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 233.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-233-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-233-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 233.0.0 delivers significant enhancements including new job configuration flags for Cloud Dataflow and Cloud ML Engine, and promotes several key features to General Availability across Cloud Filestore, Pub/Sub, and Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s instance groups and network configurations. Additionally, it updates the Cloud Firestore Emulator with new RPCs and logging, fixes a &lt;code&gt;gcloud sql connect&lt;/code&gt; whitelisting issue, and updates the &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gcloud SDK 229.0.0 Release Analysis</title><link>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-229-0-0-release-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lust.dev/gcloud/gcloud-sdk-229-0-0-release-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SDK 229.0.0 introduces significant new features, including an alpha &lt;code&gt;gcloud bq&lt;/code&gt; command group for BigQuery, Cloud Firestore index management, and Kaniko integration for Cloud Build with new flags. This release also includes the deprecation of HTTP/HTTPS health check flags in Compute Engine, the promotion of several flags and commands to beta and GA stability levels, and various updates and bug fixes for App Engine, Cloud Datastore, and Cloud Firestore emulators, alongside a &lt;code&gt;gsutil&lt;/code&gt; component update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="#breaking-changes"&gt;Annotated Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="#stats"&gt;Stats 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>